{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The DBMS acts as an interface between what two components of an enterprise-class database system?", "opta": "Database application and the database", "optb": "Data and the database", "optc": "The user and the database application", "optd": "Database application and SQL", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following products was an early implementation of the relational model developed by E.F. Codd of IBM?", "opta": "IDMS", "optb": "DB2", "optc": "dBase-II", "optd": "R:base", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following are components of a database except ________ .", "opta": "user data", "optb": "metadata", "optc": "reports", "optd": "indexes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An application where only one user accesses the database at a given time is an example of a(n) ________ .", "opta": "single-user database application", "optb": "multiuser database application", "optc": "e-commerce database application", "optd": "data mining database application", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An on-line commercial site such as Amazon.com is an example of a(n) ________ .", "opta": "single-user database application", "optb": "multiuser database application", "optc": "e-commerce database application", "optd": "data mining database application", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following products was the first to implement true relational algebra in a PC DBMS?", "opta": "IDMS", "optb": "Oracle", "optc": "dBase-II", "optd": "R:base", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "SQL stands for ________ .", "opta": "Structured Query Language", "optb": "Sequential Query Language", "optc": "Structured Question Language", "optd": "Sequential Question Language", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Because it contains a description of its own structure, a database is considered to be ________ .", "opta": "described", "optb": "metadata compatible", "optc": "self-describing", "optd": "an application program", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following are functions of a DBMS except ________ .", "opta": "creating and processing forms", "optb": "creating databases", "optc": "processing data", "optd": "administrating databases", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Helping people keep track of things is the purpose of a(n) ________ .", "opta": "database", "optb": "table", "optc": "instance", "optd": "relationship", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following products implemented the CODASYL DBTG model?", "opta": "IDMS", "optb": "DB2", "optc": "dBase-II", "optd": "R:base", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An Enterprise Resource Planning application is an example of a(n) ________ .", "opta": "single-user database application", "optb": "multiuser database application", "optc": "e-commerce database application", "optd": "data mining database application", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A DBMS that combines a DBMS and an application generator is ________ .", "opta": "Microsoft's SQL Server", "optb": "Microsoft's Access", "optc": "IBM's DB2", "optd": "Oracle Corporation's Oracle", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You have run an SQL statement that asked the DBMS to display data in a table named USER_TABLES. The results include columns of data labeled \"TableName,\" \"NumberOfColumns\" and \"PrimaryKey.\" You are looking at ________ .", "opta": "user data.", "optb": "metadata", "optc": "A report", "optd": "indexes", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not considered to be a basic element of an enterprise-class database system?", "opta": "Users", "optb": "Database applications", "optc": "DBMS", "optd": "COBOL programs", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The DBMS that is most difficult to use is ________ .", "opta": "Microsoft's SQL Server", "optb": "Microsoft's Access", "optc": "IBM's DB2", "optd": "Oracle Corporation's Oracle", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}